{
"QnAs":[
  {
    "Question": "What is SAT?",
    "Answer": "Self-Attachment Technique (SAT) is a self-help method based on creating an affectional bond with our child for nurturing positive emotions and attitudes (such as compassion cheerfulness and creativity) re-processing negative experiences and developing positive cognitive behavioural and interpersonal patterns. These goals are achieved through regular daily practice sessions involving reparenting one’s child reflecting on one’s experiences and belief systems and exercises to reduce negative affects and develop and reinforce positive attitudes and patterns."
  },
  {
    "Question": "How many protocols?",
    "Answer": "The twenty-one subprotocols of self-attachment are typically presented weekly in an eight-week course for a group of participants. It is also possible to do a shorter version of the course which is two weeks."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Can you explain what Self-Attachment Technique (SAT) involves?",
    "Answer": "Self-Attachment Technique (SAT) is a self-help method based on creating an affectional bond with our child for nurturing positive emotions and attitudes (such as compassion, cheerfulness, and creativity), re-processing negative experiences, and developing positive cognitive, behavioural, and interpersonal patterns. These goals are achieved through regular daily practice sessions involving reparenting one’s child, reflecting on one’s experiences and belief systems, and exercises to reduce negative affects and develop and reinforce positive attitudes and patterns."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What does the Self-Attachment Technique aim to achieve?",
    "Answer": "Self-Attachment Technique (SAT) is a self-help method based on creating an affectional bond with our child for nurturing positive emotions and attitudes (such as compassion, cheerfulness, and creativity), re-processing negative experiences, and developing positive cognitive, behavioural, and interpersonal patterns. These goals are achieved through regular daily practice sessions involving reparenting one’s child, reflecting on one’s experiences and belief systems, and exercises to reduce negative affects and develop and reinforce positive attitudes and patterns."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What is the structure of the Self-Attachment Technique program?",
    "Answer": "The twenty-one subprotocols of self-attachment are typically presented weekly in an eight-week course for a group of participants. It is also possible to do a shorter version of the course which is two weeks."
  },
  {
    "Question": "How is this intervention structured?",
    "Answer": "The twenty-one subprotocols of self-attachment are typically presented weekly in an eight-week course for a group of participants. It is also possible to do a shorter version of the course which is two weeks."
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "What goal should I have?",
    "Answer": "This goal should be a non-materialistic goal that guides us towards growth and self-development in society; e.g. success in an academic scientific literary philosophical athletic spiritual professional charitable manufacturing or commercial field.\nIf we don’t have a clear goal at the start of the program, we try to find it as we practice the protocols."
  },
  {
    "Question": "How many stages of self-attachment?",
    "Answer": "Secure self-attachment simulates the relationship between a child and a good parent to turn our adult self simply called adult into a parent that can help the emotional development of our childhood self simply called our child in these notes:\n1- Introduction to attachment theory and SAT\n2- Connection with the child\n3- Falling in love with the child\n4- Developmental training for the child"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Why do I need role-play?",
    "Answer": "Our problems to properly manage our emotions is usually rooted in our childhood development.\nThis means that we have not developed the skills to moderate our excitements, regulate our emotions, or have a sense of humour and laugh at times of stress.\nIn SAT, the adult learns how a good parent interacts with a child and through role-playing, they become a parent for their child.\nThe intervention strategy is based on collaboration between the adult and the child for regulating emotions and learning to laugh.\nThe adult helps the child replace the old derelict house with a grand new one with the aim of realizing the child’s potentials and higher goals."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Why can’t I feel the improvement?",
    "Answer": "Since SAT takes place through acquiring new positive habits, sustainable improvement will only take place gradually and depends on the consistent and daily repetition of the protocols.\nNon-optimal thought and behavioural patterns are developed over the course of many years in our childhood and then consolidated by repetition in later years.\nCreation of more optimal thought and behavioural patterns unsurprisingly takes months of consistent daily effort and thus requires patience and perseverance."
  },
  {
    "Question": "What are the key phases in SAT?",
    "Answer": "Secure self-attachment simulates the relationship between a child and a good parent to turn our adult self simply called adult into a parent that can help the emotional development of our childhood self simply called our child in these notes:\n1- Introduction to attachment theory and SAT\n2- Connection with the child\n3- Falling in love with the child\n4- Developmental training for the child"
  },
  {
    "Question": "How do I attain Secure Self-Attachment?",
    "Answer": "Secure self-attachment simulates the relationship between a child and a good parent to turn our adult self simply called adult into a parent that can help the emotional development of our childhood self simply called our child in these notes:\n1- Introduction to attachment theory and SAT\n2- Connection with the child\n3- Falling in love with the child\n4- Developmental training for the child"
  },
  {
    "Question": "What is the purpose of role-play in SAT?",
    "Answer": "Our problems to properly manage our emotions is usually rooted in our childhood development.\nThis means that we have not developed the skills to moderate our excitements, regulate our emotions, or have a sense of humour and laugh at times of stress.\nIn SAT, the adult learns how a good parent interacts with a child and through role-playing, they become a parent for their child.\nThe intervention strategy is based on collaboration between the adult and the child for regulating emotions and learning to laugh.\nThe adult helps the child replace the old derelict house with a grand new one with the aim of realizing the child’s potentials and higher goals."
  },
  {
    "Question": "How does role-playing contribute to SAT?",
    "Answer": "Our problems to properly manage our emotions is usually rooted in our childhood development.\nThis means that we have not developed the skills to moderate our excitements, regulate our emotions, or have a sense of humour and laugh at times of stress.\nIn SAT, the adult learns how a good parent interacts with a child and through role-playing, they become a parent for their child.\nThe intervention strategy is based on collaboration between the adult and the child for regulating emotions and learning to laugh.\nThe adult helps the child replace the old derelict house with a grand new one with the aim of realizing the child’s potentials and higher goals."
  },
  {
    "Question": "How soon will I see progress?",
    "Answer": "Since SAT takes place through acquiring new positive habits, sustainable improvement will only take place gradually and depends on the consistent and daily repetition of the protocols.\nNon-optimal thought and behavioural patterns are developed over the course of many years in our childhood and then consolidated by repetition in later years.\nCreation of more optimal thought and behavioural patterns unsurprisingly takes months of consistent daily effort and thus requires patience and perseverance."
  },
  {
    "Question": "How long will it take me to achieve my goal?",
    "Answer": "Since SAT takes place through acquiring new positive habits, sustainable improvement will only take place gradually and depends on the consistent and daily repetition of the protocols.\nNon-optimal thought and behavioural patterns are developed over the course of many years in our childhood and then consolidated by repetition in later years.\nCreation of more optimal thought and behavioural patterns unsurprisingly takes months of consistent daily effort and thus requires patience and perseverance."
  },
  
 {
  "Question": "What is attachment theory?",
  "Answer": "Attachment theory is a psychological, evolutionary, and ethological theory concerning relationships between humans. The most important tenet is that young children need to develop a relationship with at least one primary caregiver for normal social and emotional development. The theory was formulated by psychiatrist and psychoanalyst John Bowlby."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What is attachment?",
  "Answer": "Within attachment theory, the attachment means an affectional bond or tie between an individual and an attachment figure (usually a caregiver). Such bonds may be reciprocal between two adults, but between a child and a caregiver, these bonds are based on the child's need for safety, security, and protection — which is most important in infancy and childhood. In child-to-adult relationships, the child's tie is called the \"attachment\" and the caregiver's reciprocal equivalent is referred to as the \"care-giving bond\"."
 },
 {
  "Question": "Does attachment behaviour indicate security?",
  "Answer": "The strength of a child's attachment behaviour in a given circumstance does not indicate the 'strength' of the attachment bond. Some insecure children will routinely display very pronounced attachment behaviours, while many secure children find that there is no great need to engage in either intense or frequent shows of attachment behaviour."
 },
 {
  "Question": "How does attachment change from childhood to adolescence?",
  "Answer": "Childhood and adolescence allow the development of an internal working model useful for forming attachments. This internal working model is related to the individual's state of mind which develops with respect to attachment generally and explores how attachment functions in relationship dynamics based on childhood and adolescent experience. The organization of an internal working model is generally seen as leading to more stable attachments in those who develop such a model, rather than those who rely more on the individual's state of mind alone in forming new attachments.\\n\\nAge, cognitive growth, and continued social experience advance the development and complexity of the internal working model. Attachment-related behaviours lose some characteristics typical of the infant-toddler period and take on age-related tendencies. The preschool period involves the use of negotiation and bargaining. For example, four-year-olds are not distressed by separation if they and their caregiver have already negotiated a shared plan for the separation and reunion.\\n\\nIdeally, these social skills become incorporated into the internal working model to be used with other children and later with adult peers. As children move into the school years at about six years old, most develop a goal-corrected partnership with parents, in which each partner is willing to compromise in order to maintain a gratifying relationship. By middle childhood, the goal of the attachment behavioural system has changed from proximity to the attachment figure to availability. Generally, a child is content with longer separations, provided contact—or the possibility of physically reuniting, if needed—is available. Attachment behaviours such as clinging and following decline and self-reliance increase. By middle childhood (ages 7–11), there may be a shift toward mutual [coregulation](https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Coregulation) of secure-base contact in which caregiver and child negotiate methods of maintaining communication and supervision as the child moves toward a greater degree of independence.\\n\\nThe attachment system used by adolescents is seen as a \"safety regulating system\" whose main function is to promote physical and psychological safety. There are 2 different events that can trigger the attachment system. Those triggers include the presence of potential danger or stress, internal and external, and a threat of accessibility and\/or availability of an attachment figure. The ultimate goal of the attachment system is security, so during a time of danger or inaccessibility, the behavioural system accepts felt security in the context of the availability of protection. By adolescence, we are able to find security through a variety of things, such as food, exercise, and social media. Felt security can be achieved in a number of ways, and often without the physical presence of the attachment figure. Higher levels of maturity allow adolescent teens to more capably interact with their environment on their own because the environment is perceived as less threatening. Adolescents teens will also see an increase in cognitive, emotional and behavioural maturity that dictates whether or not teens are less likely to experience conditions that activate their need for an attachment figure. For example, when teenagers get sick and stay home from school, surely they want their parents to be home so they can take care of them, but they are also able to stay home by themselves without experiencing serious amounts of distress."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What attachment styles are there in adults?",
  "Answer": "Attachment theory was extended to adult romantic relationships in the late 1980s by Cindy Hazan and Phillip Shaver. Four styles of attachment have been identified in adults: secure, anxious-preoccupied, dismissive-avoidant and fearful-avoidant. These roughly correspond to infant classifications: secure, insecure-ambivalent, insecure-avoidant and disorganized\/disoriented."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What are the biological explanations of attachment?",
  "Answer": "The quality of caregiving received in infancy and childhood directly affects an individual's neurological systems which control stress regulation. In psychophysiological research on attachment, the two main areas studied have been [autonomic responses](https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Autonomic_nervous_system), such as heart rate or respiration, and the activity of the hypothalamic-pituitary-adrenal [axis](https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Hypothalamic%E2%80%93pituitary%E2%80%93adrenal_axis), a system that is responsible for the body's reaction to [stress](https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Stress_(biology). Infants' physiological responses have been measured during the Strange Situation procedure looking at individual differences in infant temperament and the extent to which attachment acts as a moderator. Recent studies convey that early attachment relationships become molecularly instilled into the being, thus affecting later immune system functioning. Empirical evidence communicates that early negative experiences produce pro-inflammatory phenotype cells in the immune system, which is directly related to cardiovascular disease, autoimmune diseases, and certain types of cancer.\\n\\nRecent improvements involving methods of research have enabled researchers to further investigate the neural correlates of attachment in humans. These advances include identifying key brain structures, neural circuits, neurotransmitter systems, and neuropeptides, and how they are involved in attachment system functioning and can indicate more about a certain individual, even predict their behaviour. There is initial evidence that caregiving and attachment involve both unique and overlapping brain regions. Another issue is the role of inherited genetic factors in shaping attachments: for example, one type of [polymorphism](\/wiki\/Polymorphism_(biology) of the gene coding for the [D2](https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Dopamine_receptor_D2) [dopamine receptor](https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Dopamine_receptor) has been linked to anxious attachment and another in the gene for the [5-HT2A](https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/5-HT2A_receptor) [serotonin receptor](https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Serotonin_receptor) with avoidant attachment.\\n\\nStudies show that attachment in adulthood is simultaneously related to biomarkers of immunity. For example, individuals with an avoidance attachment style produce higher levels of the pro-inflammatory cytokine interleukin-6 (IL-6) when reacting to an interpersonal stressor, while individuals representing an anxious attachment style tend to have elevated cortisol production and lower numbers of T cells. Although children vary genetically and each individual requires different attachment relationships, there is consistent evidence that maternal warmth during infancy and childhood creates a safe haven for individuals resulting in superior immune system functioning. One theoretical basis for this is that it makes biological sense for children to vary in their susceptibility to rearing influence."
 },
 {
  "Question": "How is attachment theory related to crime?",
  "Answer": "Attachment theory has often been applied in the discipline of [criminology](https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Criminology). It has been used in an attempt to identify causal mechanisms in criminal behaviour – with uses ranging from [offender profiling](https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Offender_profiling), a better understanding of types of offence and the pursuit of preventative policy. It has been found that disturbances early on in child-caregiver relationships are a risk factor for criminality. Attachment theory in this context has been described as \"perhaps the most influential of contemporary psychoanalytically oriented theories of crime\"."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What are the practical applications of attachment theory?",
  "Answer": "As a theory of [socioemotional development](https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Developmental_psychology \"Developmental psychology\"), attachment theory has implications and practical applications in social policy, decisions about the care and welfare of children and mental health."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What are the attachment behaviours in infants?",
  "Answer": "Pre-attachment behaviours occur in the first six months of life. During the first phase (the first eight weeks), infants smile, babble, and cry to attract the attention of potential caregivers. Although infants of this age learn to discriminate between caregivers, these behaviours are directed at anyone in the vicinity.\\n\\nDuring the second phase (two to six months), the infant discriminates between familiar and unfamiliar adults, becoming more responsive toward the caregiver; following and clinging are added to the range of behaviours. The infant's behaviour toward the caregiver becomes organized on a goal-directed basis to achieve the conditions that make it feel secure.\\n\\nBy the end of the first year, the infant is able to display a range of attachment behaviours designed to maintain proximity. These manifest as protesting the caregiver's departure, greeting the caregiver's return, clinging when frightened, and following when able.\\n\\nWith the development of locomotion, the infant begins to use the caregiver or caregivers as a \"safe base\" from which to explore. Infant exploration is greater when the caregiver is present because the infant's attachment system is relaxed and it is free to explore. If the caregiver is inaccessible or unresponsive, attachment behaviour is more strongly exhibited. Anxiety, fear, illness, and fatigue will cause a child to increase attachment behaviours.\\n\\nAfter the second year, as the child begins to see the caregiver as an independent person, a more complex and goal-corrected partnership is formed. Children begin to notice others' goals and feelings and plan their actions accordingly."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What are the principles of attachment theory?",
  "Answer": "Modern attachment theory is based on three principles:\\n\\n1.  Bonding is an intrinsic human need.\\n2.  Regulation of emotion and fear to enhance vitality.\\n3.  Promoting adaptiveness and growth."
 },
 {
  "Question": "How is attachment related to different cultures?",
  "Answer": "In Western culture child-rearing, there is a focus on single attachment to primarily the mother. This dyadic model is not the only strategy of attachment producing a secure and emotionally adept child. Having a single, dependably responsive and sensitive caregiver (namely the mother) does not guarantee the ultimate success of the child. Results from Israeli, Dutch and east African studies show children with multiple caregivers grow up not only feeling secure but developed \"more enhanced capacities to view the world from multiple perspectives.\" This evidence can be more readily found in hunter-gatherer communities, like those that exist in rural Tanzania.\\n\\nIn hunter-gatherer communities, in the past and present, mothers are the primary caregivers but share the maternal responsibility of ensuring the child's survival with a variety of different [allomothers](https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Allomothering). So while the mother is important, she is not the only opportunity for relational attachment a child can make. Several group members (with or without blood relation) contribute to the task of bringing up a child, sharing the parenting role and therefore can be sources of multiple attachments. There is evidence of this communal parenting throughout history that \"would have significant implications for the evolution of multiple attachments.\"\\n\\nIn \"non-metropolis\" India (where \"dual-income nuclear families\" are more the norm and dyadic mother relationship is), where a family normally consists of 3 generations (and if lucky 4: great-grandparents, grandparents, parents, and child or children), the child or children by default have four to six caregivers from whom to select their \"attachment figure\". And a child's \"uncles and aunts\" (father's siblings and their spouses) also contribute to the child's psycho-social enrichment.\\n\\nAlthough it has been debated for years, and there are differences across cultures, research has shown that the three basic aspects of attachment theory are, to some degree, universal. Studies in Israel and Japan resulted in findings that diverge from a number of studies completed in Western Europe and the United States. The prevailing hypotheses are: 1) that secure attachment is the most desirable state, and the most prevalent; 2) maternal sensitivity influences infant attachment patterns; and 3) specific infant attachments predict later social and cognitive competence."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What is the significance of attachment patterns?",
  "Answer": "There is an extensive body of research demonstrating a significant association between attachment organizations and children's functioning across multiple domains. Early insecure attachment does not necessarily predict difficulties, but it is a liability for the child, particularly if similar parental behaviours continue throughout childhood. Compared to that of securely attached children, the adjustment of insecure children in many spheres of life is not as soundly based, putting their future relationships in jeopardy. Although the link is not fully established by research and there are other influences besides attachment, secure infants are more likely to become socially competent than their insecure peers. Relationships formed with peers influence the acquisition of social skills, intellectual development and the formation of social identity. Classification of children's peer status (popular, neglected or rejected) has been found to predict subsequent adjustment. Insecure children, particularly avoidant children, are especially vulnerable to family risk. Their social and behavioural problems increase or decline with deterioration or improvement in parenting. However, an early secure attachment appears to have a lasting protective function. As with attachment to parental figures, subsequent experiences may alter the course of development.\\n\\nStudies have suggested that infants with a high risk for [autism spectrum disorders](https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Autism_spectrum_disorders) (ASD) may express attachment security differently from infants with a low risk for ASD. Behavioural problems and social competence in insecure children increase or decline with deterioration or improvement in the quality of parenting and the degree of risk in the family environment."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What is securely attached in adults?",
  "Answer": "Securely attached adults have been \"linked to a high need for achievement and a low fear of failure (Elliot & Reis, 2003)\". They will positively approach a task with the goal of mastering it and have an appetite for exploration in achievement settings (Elliot & Reis, 2003). Research shows that securely attached adults have a \"low level of personal distress and high levels of concern for others\". Due to their high rates of [self-efficacy](https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Self-efficacy), securely attached adults typically do not hesitate to remove a person having a negative impact on problematic situations they are facing. This calm response is representative of the securely attached adult's emotionally regulated response to threats that many studies have supported in the face of diverse situations. Adult secure attachment comes from an individual's early connection with their caregiver(s), genes and romantic experiences.\\n\\nWithin romantic relationships, a securely attached adult will appear in the following ways: excellent conflict resolution, mentally flexible, effective communicators, avoidance of manipulation, comfortable with closeness without fearfulness of being enmeshed, quickly forgiving, viewing sex and emotional intimacy as one, believing they can positively impact their relationship, and caring for their partner in the way they want to be cared for. In summation, they are great partners who treat their spouses very well, as they are not afraid to give positive and ask for their needs to be met. Securely attached adults believe that there are \"many potential partners that would be responsive to their needs\", and if they come across an individual who is not meeting their needs, they will typically lose interest very quickly. In a study comparing secure-secure and secure-various attachment style relationships, there was no fluctuation in positive relational functioning. However, in any combination of two partners with attachment styles outside of security, the relationships showed high levels of negative relationship functioning. This research indicates that it only takes one securely attached partner within a romantic relationship to maintain healthy, emotional relationship functioning.\\n\\nSexually, securely attached individuals are less likely to be involved in one-night stands or sexual activity outside of the primary relationship, and more likely to report mutual initiation and enjoyment of sex."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What is anxious-preoccupied in adults?",
  "Answer": "Anxious-preoccupied adults seek high levels of intimacy, approval and responsiveness from partners, becoming overly dependent. They tend to be less trusting, have less positive views about themselves and their partners, and may exhibit high levels of emotional expressiveness, worry and impulsiveness in their relationships. The anxiety that adults feel prevents the establishment of satisfactory defence exclusion. Thus, it is possible that individuals that have been anxiously attached to their attachment figure or figures have not been able to develop sufficient defences against separation anxiety. Because of their lack of preparation these individuals will then overreact to the anticipation of separation or the actual separation from their attachment figure. The anxiety comes from an individual's intense and\/or unstable relationship that leaves the anxious or preoccupied individual relatively defenceless. Adults with this attachment style tend to look way too far into things, whether that's a text message or a face-to-face conversation. Their thoughts and actions can lead to a painful cycle of self-fulfilling prophecies and even self-sabotage. They often seek a dismissive-avoidant partner."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What is dismissive-avoidant in adults?",
  "Answer": "Dismissive-avoidant adults desire a high level of independence, often appearing to avoid attachment altogether. They view themselves as self-sufficient, invulnerable to attachment feelings and not needing close relationships. They tend to suppress their feelings, dealing with conflict by distancing themselves from partners of whom they often have a poor opinion. Adults lack the interest in forming close relationships and maintaining emotional closeness with the people around them. They have a great amount of distrust in others but at the same time possess a positive model of self, they would prefer to invest in their own ego skills. Because of their distrust they cannot be convinced that other people have the ability to deliver emotional support. They try to create high levels of self-esteem by investing disproportionately in their abilities or accomplishments. These adults maintain their positive views of self, based on their personal achievements and competence rather than searching for and feeling acceptance from others. These adults will explicitly reject or minimize the importance of emotional attachment and passively avoid relationships when they feel as though they are becoming too close. They strive for self-reliance and independence. When it comes to the opinions of others about themselves, they are very indifferent and are relatively hesitant to positive feedback from their peers. Dismissive avoidance can also be explained as the result of defensive deactivation of the attachment system to avoid potential rejection or genuine disregard for interpersonal closeness.\\n\\nDismissive-avoidant individuals tend to report activities reflecting low psychological intimacy (one-night sex, extra-dyadic sex, sex without love), as well as less enjoyment of physical contact. Research has demonstrated that for both sexes, the insecure-ambivalent attachment was related to the enjoyment of holding and caressing, but not to more clearly sexual behaviours."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What is fearful-avoidant in adults?",
  "Answer": "Fearful-avoidant adults have mixed feelings about close relationships, both desiring and feeling uncomfortable with emotional closeness. They tend to mistrust their partners and view themselves as unworthy. Like dismissive-avoidant adults, fearful-avoidant adults tend to seek less intimacy, suppressing their feelings."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What are the relationships involving people with different attachment styles?",
  "Answer": "Relationally, insecure individuals tend to be partnered with insecure individuals, and secure individuals with secure individuals. Insecure relationships tend to be enduring but less emotionally satisfying compared to the relationship(s) of two securely attached individuals.\\n\\nAttachment styles are activated from the first date onwards and impact relationship dynamics and how a relationship ends. Secure attachment has been shown to allow for better conflict resolution in a relationship and for one's ability to exit an unsatisfying relationship compared to other attachment types. Secure individuals' authentic high self-esteem and positive view of others allow for this as they are confident that they will find another relationship. Secure attachment has also been shown to allow for the successful processing of relational losses (e.g. death, rejection, infidelity, abandonment etc.) The attachment has also been shown to impact caregiving behaviour in relationships (Shaver & Cassidy, 2018)."
 },
 {
  "Question": "How to assess and measure attachment?",
  "Answer": "There are a number of different measures of adult attachment, the most common being self-report questionnaires and coded interviews based on the [Adult Attachment Interview](\/wiki\/Attachment_measures#Adult_Attachment_Interview_.28AAI.29). The various measures were developed primarily as research tools, for different purposes and addressing different domains, for example, romantic relationships, platonic relationships, parental relationships or peer relationships. Some classify an adult's state of mind with respect to attachment and attachment patterns by reference to childhood experiences, while others assess relationship behaviours and security regarding parents and peers."
 },
 {
  "Question": "How is adult attachment associated with other traits?",
  "Answer": "Adult attachment styles are related to individual differences in the ways in which adults experience and manage their emotions. Recent meta-analyses link insecure attachment styles to lower emotional intelligence and lower trait mindfulness."
 },
 {
  "Question": "How is attachment related to offenses?",
  "Answer": "Since early childhood relationships can influence interpersonal relationships throughout the lifespan, attachment theory has been applied in research into particular crimes, particularly those which tend to occur within close relational ties.\\n\\nDisrupted attachment patterns from childhood have been identified as a risk factor for domestic violence. These disruptions in childhood can prevent the formation of a secure attachment relationship, and in turn, adversely affect a healthy way to deal with stress. In adulthood, a lack of coping mechanisms can result in intense conflict resulting in violent behaviour. Bowlby's theory of functional anger states that children signal to their caregiver that their attachment needs are not being met by the use of angry behaviour. This has been extended to theorize why domestic violence occurs; an adult with consistent experience of insecure attachment may use physical violence to express their attachment needs not being met by their partners. This perception of low support from partners has been identified as a strong predictor of male violence. Other predictors have been named as a perceived deficiency in maternal love in childhood, and low self-esteem. It has also been found that individuals with a dismissive attachment style, often seen in an antisocial\/narcissistic-narcissistic subtype of the offender, tend to be emotionally abusive as well as violent. Individuals in the borderline\/emotionally dependent subtype have traits that originate from insecure attachment in childhood and tend to have high levels of anger.\\n\\nIt has been found that sexual offenders have significantly less secure maternal and paternal attachments compared with non-offenders which suggests that insecure attachments in infancy persist into adulthood. In a recent study, 57% of sexual offenders were found to be of a preoccupied attachment style. There is also evidence that suggests subtypes of sexual crime can have different attachment styles. Dismissive individuals tend to be hostile towards others, and are more likely to offend violently against adult women. By contrast, child abusers are more likely to have preoccupied attachment styles as the tendency to seek approval from others becomes distorted and attachment relationships become sexualized."
 },
 {
  "Question": "Who can form attachment?",
  "Answer": "Although it is usual for the mother to be the primary attachment figure, infants will form attachments to any carer who is sensitive and responsive in social interactions with them."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What are different attachment styles during adolescence?",
  "Answer": "Here are the attachment style differences during adolescence:\\n\\n*   Secure adolescents are expected to hold their mothers at a higher rate than all other support figures, including fathers, significant others, and best friends.\\n*   Insecure adolescents identify more strongly with their peers than their parents as their primary attachment figures. Their friends are seen as a significantly strong source of attachment support.\\n*   Dismissing adolescents rate their parents as a less significant source of attachment support and would consider themselves as their primary attachment figure.\\n*   Preoccupied adolescents would rate their parents as their primary source of attachment support and would consider themselves as a much less significant source of attachment support."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What are different attachment patterns?",
  "Answer": "There are four attachment patterns: secure attachment, anxious-ambivalent attachment, anxious-avoidant and dismissive-avoidant attachment, and disorganized\/disoriented attachment."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What is secure attachment?",
  "Answer": "A toddler who is securely attached to his or her parent (or another familiar caregiver) will explore freely while the caregiver is present, typically engages with strangers, is often visibly upset when the caregiver departs and is generally happy to see the caregiver return. The extent of exploration and of distress are affected, however, by the child's temperamental makeup and situational factors as well as by attachment status. A child's attachment is largely influenced by their primary caregiver's sensitivity to their needs. Parents who consistently (or almost always) respond to their child's needs will create securely attached, children. Such children are certain that their parents will be responsive to their needs and communications.\\n\\nSecurely attached children are best able to explore when they have the knowledge of a secure base (their caregiver) to return to in times of need. When assistance is given, this bolsters the sense of security and also, assuming the parent's assistance is helpful, educates the child on how to cope with the same problem in the future. Therefore, secure attachment can be seen as the most adaptive attachment style. According to some psychological researchers, a child becomes securely attached when the parent is available and able to meet the needs of the child in a responsive and appropriate manner. In infancy and early childhood, if parents are caring and attentive towards their children, those children will be more prone to secure attachment."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What is anxious-ambivalent attachment?",
  "Answer": "Anxious-ambivalent attachment is also misnamed as \"resistant attachment\". In general, a child with an anxious-ambivalent pattern of attachment will typically explore little and is often wary of strangers, even when the parent is present. When the caregiver departs, the child is often highly distressed showing behaviours such as crying or screaming. The child is generally ambivalent when the caregiver returns. The anxious-ambivalent strategy is a response to unpredictably responsive caregiving, and the displays of anger or helplessness towards the caregiver on reunion can be regarded as a conditional strategy for maintaining the availability of the caregiver by preemptively taking control of the interaction.\\n\\nResearch done by McCarthy and Taylor (1999) found that children with abusive childhood experiences were more likely to develop ambivalent attachments. The study also found that children with ambivalent attachments were more likely to experience difficulties in maintaining intimate relationships as adults"
 },
 {
  "Question": "What is anxious-avoidant and dismissive-avoidant attachment?",
  "Answer": "An infant with an anxious-avoidant pattern of attachment will avoid or ignore the caregiver—showing little emotion when the caregiver departs or returns. The infant will not explore very much regardless of who is there. Infants classified as anxious-avoidant represented a puzzle in the early 1970s. They did not exhibit distress on separation, and either ignored the caregiver on their return or showed some tendency to approach together with some tendency to ignore or turn away from the caregiver. Ainsworth and Bell theorized that the apparently unruffled behaviour of the avoidant infants was in fact a mask for distress, a hypothesis later evidenced through studies of the heart rate of avoidant infants.\\n\\nAinsworth's narrative records showed that infants avoided the caregiver in the stressful Strange Situation Procedure when they had a history of experiencing rebuff of attachment behaviour. The infant's needs were frequently not met and the infant had come to believe that communication of emotional needs had no influence on the caregiver.\\n\\nMain proposed that avoidance has two functions for an infant whose caregiver is consistently unresponsive to their needs. Firstly, avoidant behaviour allows the infant to maintain a conditional proximity with the caregiver: close enough to maintain protection, but distant enough to avoid rebuff. Secondly, the cognitive processes organising avoidant behaviour could help direct attention away from the unfulfilled desire for closeness with the caregiver—avoiding a situation in which the child is overwhelmed with emotion (\"disorganized distress\"), and therefore unable to maintain control of themselves and achieve even conditional proximity."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What is disorganized\/disoriented attachment?",
  "Answer": "In the Strange Situation, the attachment system is expected to be activated by the departure and return of the caregiver. If the behaviour of the infant does not appear to the observer to be coordinated in a smooth way across episodes to achieve either proximity or some relative proximity with the caregiver, then it is considered 'disorganized' as it indicates a disruption or flooding of the attachment system (e.g. by fear). Infant behaviours in the Strange Situation Protocol coded as disorganized\/disoriented include overt displays of fear; contradictory behaviours or effects occurring simultaneously or sequentially; stereotypic, asymmetric, misdirected or jerky movements; or freezing and apparent dissociation. Lyons-Ruth has urged, however, that it should be more widely \"recognized that 52% of disorganized infants continue to approach the caregiver, seek comfort, and cease their distress without clear ambivalent or avoidant behaviour\"."
 },
 {
  "Question": "How many protocols?",
  "Answer": "The twenty-one subprotocols of self-attachment are typically presented weekly in an eight-week course for a group of participants. It is also possible to do a shorter version of the course that lasts for two weeks."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What is SAT?",
  "Answer": "Self-Attachment Technique (SAT) is a self-help method, based on creating an affectional bond with our child, for nurturing positive emotions and attitudes (such as compassion, cheerfulness and creativity), re-processing negative experiences, and developing positive cognitive, behavioural and interpersonal patterns. These goals are achieved through regular daily practice sessions involving reparenting one’s child, reflecting on one’s experiences and belief systems, and exercises to reduce negative affects, and develop and reinforce positive attitudes and patterns."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What is self-attachment theory?",
  "Answer": "Self-Attachment Technique (SAT) is a self-help method, based on creating an affectional bond with our child, for nurturing positive emotions and attitudes (such as compassion, cheerfulness and creativity), re-processing negative experiences, and developing positive cognitive, behavioural and interpersonal patterns. These goals are achieved through regular daily practice sessions involving reparenting one’s child, reflecting on one’s experiences and belief systems, and exercises to reduce negative affects, and develop and reinforce positive attitudes and patterns."
 },
 {
  "Question": "How many stages of self-attachment?",
  "Answer": "4"
 },
 {
  "Question": "What goal should I have?",
  "Answer": "This goal should be a non-materialistic goal that guides us towards growth and self-development in society; e.g. success in an academic, scientific, literary, philosophical, athletic, spiritual, professional, charitable, manufacturing, or commercial field."
 },
 {
  "Question": "Can I have goals like making money?",
  "Answer": "This goal should be a non-materialistic goal"
 },
 {
  "Question": "How many stages of self-attachment?",
  "Answer": "Secure self-attachment simulates the relationship between a child and a good parent to turn our adult self, simply called adult, into a parent that can help the emotional development of our childhood self, simply called our child in these notes: The four stages of SAT are 1- Introduction to attachment theory 2- Connecting with the child 3- Falling in love with the child 4- Developmental training for the child"
 },
 {
  "Question": "What is Stage 1 of SAT?",
  "Answer": "Stage One: Introduction to SAT**\\n\\nSAT is a technique to enhance mental health.\\n\\nLike any other form of self-improvement method, SAT entails serious effort, patience and perseverance on our behalf.\\n\\nSAT protocols simulate the parent-child relationship, which may at first seem strange.\\n\\nTherefore, we should make ourselves informed by attachment theory in general and the scientific hypotheses of self-attachment technique."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What is Stage 2 of SAT?",
  "Answer": "**Stage Two: Connecting with the child**\\n\\nWe try to distinguish between our adult, i.e. our thinking and reasoning capacity that is more dominant when we are calm, and our child, i.e. the emotions and affects that become more dominant under stress and crisis.\\n\\nWe do this with protocols that involve looking at the two contrasting childhood photos, referred to for convenience as “happy” and “unhappy” photos. \\n\\nBy looking at these two contrasting photos\/avatars and recalling past events and what we have heard from others about our childhood, we gradually think about our early years to construct a basic psychological portrait of the child and our feelings, affects, and emotional problems with our parents and other significant figures in early childhood."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What is Stage 3 of SAT?",
  "Answer": "**Stage Three: Falling in love with the child**\\n\\nIn this stage, we establish an imaginative but passionate loving relationship with the child.\\n\\nThis falling in love will activate the reward system of the brain by releasing happy hormones and neurotransmitters, which create the motivation, capacity and energy needed to carry out self-attachment protocols to raise the child to emotional maturity.\\n\\nThroughout history, human beings have created passionate and warm relationships with animate and inanimate objects and concepts and have endowed immense significance to these relationships to use them to regulate their emotions.\\n\\nIn self-attachment, the theoretical basis of falling in love with the child is primary narcissism or innate self-love, which is hypothesized to exist in all individuals. With emotional maturity, primary narcissism is usually moderated by emotional development, but childhood trauma can cause its perpetuation and even aggravation.\\n\\nSelf-attachment makes use of the existing primary narcissism in human beings, in other words, our intrinsic love of ourselves.\\n\\nThe goal is that by falling in love with the child, we become able to have a new emotional birth and growth that will eventually contain our narcissism.\\n\\nHowever, falling in love with the child is quite different from being in love with one’s self.\\n\\nOur adult falls in love with our child as good parents are in love with their children, and attends to the child lovingly but at the same time contain the anti-social selfishness and unreasonable egoistic expectations of the child."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What is Stage 4 of SAT?",
  "Answer": "*Stage Four: Reparenting**\\n\\nOur adults must always remember the vow for the unwavering bond with the child.\\n\\nWe choose a short phrase such as “You are my beloved”.\\n\\nWe repeatedly utter it loudly while we look at the happy and unhappy photos\/avatars; the aim is to become habituated to uttering this phrase.\\n\\nWe recite one or two examples of the happy love songs we selected in Stage Three.\\n\\nWe loudly repeat these songs using our whole body.\\n\\nThe goal is that by memorizing these songs, we will get used to reciting them, and as a result always keep the relationship with the child in mind. \\n\\nHabituation to sing the selected happy love songs is so strengthened in this way that we develop a tendency to spontaneously, unintentionally and effortlessly engage in reciting these songs in all kinds of circumstances.\\n\\nAs we become more habituated to singing these songs, we will be able to engage in reciting them even when we are depressed or anxious.\\n\\nThis will help reduce our pain and remind us of the loving relationship with the child.\\n\\nThese exercises help keep the secretion of serotonin, dopamine and other mood-enhancing neurotransmitters at a high level.\\n\\nThis will lead to more hope, motivation, and energy, and will have a moderating effect on depression and anxiety."
 },
 {
  "Question": "Can you describe the first phase of the Self-Attachment Technique?",
  "Answer": "Stage One: Introduction to SAT\n\nSAT is a technique to enhance mental health.\n\nLike any other form of self-improvement method, SAT entails serious effort, patience and perseverance on our behalf.\n\nSAT protocols simulate the parent-child relationship, which may at first seem strange.\n\nTherefore, we should make ourselves informed by attachment theory in general and the scientific hypotheses of self-attachment technique."
},
{
  "Question": "What does the initial stage of Self-Attachment Therapy involve?",
  "Answer": "Stage One: Introduction to SAT\n\nSAT is a technique to enhance mental health.\n\nLike any other form of self-improvement method, SAT entails serious effort, patience and perseverance on our behalf.\n\nSAT protocols simulate the parent-child relationship, which may at first seem strange.\n\nTherefore, we should make ourselves informed by attachment theory in general and the scientific hypotheses of self-attachment technique."
},
{
  "Question": "What is done in the second stage of SAT?",
  "Answer": "Stage Two: Connecting with the child\n\nWe try to distinguish between our adult, i.e. our thinking and reasoning capacity that is more dominant when we are calm, and our child, i.e. the emotions and affects that become more dominant under stress and crisis.\n\nWe do this with protocols that involve looking at the two contrasting childhood photos, referred to for convenience as 'happy' and 'unhappy' photos. \n\nBy looking at these two contrasting photos/avatars and recalling past events and what we have heard from others about our childhood, we gradually think about our early years to construct a basic psychological portrait of the child and our feelings, affects, and emotional problems with our parents and other significant figures in early childhood."
},
{
  "Question": "What does Stage 2 of SAT involve?",
  "Answer": "Stage Two: Connecting with the child\n\nWe try to distinguish between our adult, i.e. our thinking and reasoning capacity that is more dominant when we are calm, and our child, i.e. the emotions and affects that become more dominant under stress and crisis.\n\nWe do this with protocols that involve looking at the two contrasting childhood photos, referred to for convenience as 'happy' and 'unhappy' photos. \n\nBy looking at these two contrasting photos/avatars and recalling past events and what we have heard from others about our childhood, we gradually think about our early years to construct a basic psychological portrait of the child and our feelings, affects, and emotional problems with our parents and other significant figures in early childhood."
},
{
  "Question": "Explain the third stage of SAT?",
  "Answer": "Stage Three: Falling in love with the child\n\nIn this stage, we establish an imaginative but passionate loving relationship with the child.\n\nThis falling in love will activate the reward system of the brain by releasing happy hormones and neurotransmitters, which create the motivation, capacity and energy needed to carry out self-attachment protocols to raise the child to emotional maturity.\n\nThroughout history, human beings have created passionate and warm relationships with animate and inanimate objects and concepts and have endowed immense significance to these relationships to use them to regulate their emotions.\n\nIn self-attachment, the theoretical basis of falling in love with the child is primary narcissism or innate self-love, which is hypothesized to exist in all individuals. With emotional maturity, primary narcissism is usually moderated by emotional development, but childhood trauma can cause its perpetuation and even aggravation.\n\nSelf-attachment makes use of the existing primary narcissism in human beings, in other words, our intrinsic love of ourselves.\n\nThe goal is that by falling in love with the child, we become able to have a new emotional birth and growth that will eventually contain our narcissism.\n\nHowever, falling in love with the child is quite different from being in love with one’s self.\n\nOur adult falls in love with our child as good parents are in love with their children, and attends to the child lovingly but at the same time contain the anti-social selfishness and unreasonable egoistic expectations of the child."
},
{
  "Question": "What occurs during the fourth phase of the Self-Attachment Therapy process?",
  "Answer": "Stage Four: Reparenting\n\nOur adults must always remember the vow for the unwavering bond with the child.\n\nWe choose a short phrase such as 'You are my beloved'.\n\nWe repeatedly utter it loudly while we look at the happy and unhappy photos/avatars; the aim is to become habituated to uttering this phrase.\n\nWe recite one or two examples of the happy love songs we selected in Stage Three.\n\nWe loudly repeat these songs using our whole body.\n\nThe goal is that by memorizing these songs, we will get used to reciting them, and as a result always keep the relationship with the child in mind. \n\nHabituation to sing the selected happy love songs is so strengthened in this way that we develop a tendency to spontaneously, unintentionally and effortlessly engage in reciting these songs in all kinds of circumstances.\n\nAs we become more habituated to singing these songs, we will be able to engage in reciting them even when we are depressed or anxious.\n\nThis will help reduce our pain and remind us of the loving relationship with the child.\n\nThese exercises help keep the secretion of serotonin, dopamine and other mood-enhancing neurotransmitters at a high level.\n\nThis will lead to more hope, motivation, and energy, and will have a moderating effect on depression and anxiety."
},

 {
  "Question": "Why do I need role-play?",
  "Answer": "Our problems with properly managing our emotions are usually rooted in our childhood development. This means that we have not developed the skills to moderate our excitements, regulate our emotions, or have a sense of humour and laugh at times of stress. In SAT, the adult learns how a good parent interacts with a child, and through role-playing, they become a parent to their child.  The intervention strategy is based on collaboration between the adult and the child for regulating emotions and learning to laugh. The adult helps the child replace the old derelict house with a brand new one with the aim of realizing the child’s potential and higher goals."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What if I don't have any goal?",
  "Answer": "If we don’t have a clear goal at the start of the program, we try to find it as we practice the protocols."
 },
 {
  "Question": "Why can't I feel the improvement?",
  "Answer": "Since SAT takes place through acquiring new positive habits, sustainable improvement will only take place gradually and depends on the consistent and daily repetition of the protocols. Non-optimal thought and behavioural patterns are developed over the course of many years in our childhood, and then consolidated by repetition in later years. Creation of more optimal thought and behavioural patterns unsurprisingly takes months of consistent daily effort and thus requires patience and perseverance."
 },
 {
  "Question": "How many protocols?",
  "Answer": "twenty-one"
 },
 {
  "Question": "How long is the course?",
  "Answer": "The complete course takes eight weeks, but it is possible to do a shorter version of the course in two weeks."
 },
 {
  "Question": "How much time?",
  "Answer": "Each day, practice exercises for 10-15 minutes twice a day"
 },
 {
  "Question": "Why do we fall in love with the child?",
  "Answer": "In self-attachment, the theoretical basis of falling in love with the child is primary narcissism or innate self-love, which is hypothesized to exist in all individuals."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What attitude should I have to my child self?",
  "Answer": "One of the principles of self-attachment is to have a warm and compassionate attitude towards our child and their emotional problems. Later this compassion is extended to other people."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What attitude should I have to my child self?",
  "Answer": "Compassion"
 },
 {
  "Question": "How can we learn compassion?",
  "Answer": "We can find examples and role models of good parents interacting with their children in our family, among friends, in the parks and playgrounds or on the Web: they show affection without spoiling their children, hugging and caressing them at times of stress or even in ordinary circumstances."
 },
 {
  "Question": "Why do we fall in love with the child?",
  "Answer": "This falling in love will activate the reward system of the brain by releasing happy hormones and neurotransmitters, which create the motivation, capacity and energy needed to carry out self-attachment protocols to raise the child to emotional maturity."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What is the theoretical reason behind falling in love with our child in SAT?",
  "Answer": "In self-attachment, the theoretical basis of falling in love with the child is primary narcissism or innate self-love, which is hypothesized to exist in all individuals."
},
{
  "Question": "What is the psychological basis for developing a loving relationship with our child in self-attachment?",
  "Answer": "In self-attachment, the theoretical basis of falling in love with the child is primary narcissism or innate self-love, which is hypothesized to exist in all individuals."
},
{
  "Question": "What kind of emotional stance is recommended towards the child in self-attachment therapy?",
  "Answer": "One of the principles of self-attachment is to have a warm and compassionate attitude towards our child and their emotional problems. Later this compassion is extended to other people."
},
{
  "Question": "What is the recommended approach to dealing with the emotional issues of our child in SAT?",
  "Answer": "One of the principles of self-attachment is to have a warm and compassionate attitude towards our child and their emotional problems. Later this compassion is extended to other people."
},
{
  "Question": "In self-attachment, what core emotion should we nurture towards our child self?",
  "Answer": "Compassion"
},
{
  "Question": "How do we develop compassion in the context of self-attachment?",
  "Answer": "We can find examples and role models of good parents interacting with their children in our family, among friends, in the parks and playgrounds or on the Web: they show affection without spoiling their children, hugging and caressing them at times of stress or even in ordinary circumstances."
},
{
  "Question": "What practical ways are there to learn compassion within self-attachment?",
  "Answer": "We can find examples and role models of good parents interacting with their children in our family, among friends, in the parks and playgrounds or on the Web: they show affection without spoiling their children, hugging and caressing them at times of stress or even in ordinary circumstances."
},
{
  "Question": "What neurobiological changes result from falling in love with our child in SAT?",
  "Answer": "This falling in love will activate the reward system of the brain by releasing happy hormones and neurotransmitters, which create the motivation, capacity and energy needed to carry out self-attachment protocols to raise the child to emotional maturity."
},
{
  "Question": "How does falling in love with our child affect our brain chemistry in self-attachment?",
  "Answer": "This falling in love will activate the reward system of the brain by releasing happy hormones and neurotransmitters, which create the motivation, capacity and energy needed to carry out self-attachment protocols to raise the child to emotional maturity."
},

 {
  "Question": "How is SAT related to role-playing?",
  "Answer": "SAT is a type of double role-playing game in which the individual plays the role of the child and the adult simultaneously."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What is SAT?",
  "Answer": "SAT is a technique to enhance mental health."
 },
 {
  "Question": "Why do we fall in love with the child?",
  "Answer": "The goal is that by falling in love with the child, we become able to have a new emotional birth and growth that will eventually contain our narcissism. "
 },
 {
  "Question": "Is falling in love with the child the same as being in love with oneself?",
  "Answer": "Falling in love with a child is quite different from being in love with one’s self. Our adult falls in love with our child as good parents are in love with their children, and attend to the child lovingly but at the same time contain the anti-social selfishness and unreasonable egoistic expectations of the child."
 },
 {
  "Question": "Is falling in love with the child the same as being in love with oneself?",
  "Answer": "Falling in love with the child is quite different from being in love with one’s self."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What are examples of songs for falling in love with the child?",
  "Answer": "My Heart Will Go On (James Horner), What A Wonderful World (Sam Cooke)."
 },
 {
  "Question": "Why do we need attachment of nature?",
  "Answer": "Attachment to nature is an effective way to increase joy and reduce negative emotions."
 },
 {
  "Question": "Why do we need to speak out loud to the child?",
  "Answer": "The purpose of speaking out loud to the child is to create an emotional bond with them and help in their emotional development, to higher levels of maturity. It is through speaking aloud with the child that we can develop into compassionate, creative, happy individuals and reach our goals."
 },
 {
  "Question": "Why do we need to speak out loud to the child?",
  "Answer": "To create an emotional bond with them and help in their emotional development, to higher levels of maturity"
 },
 {
  "Question": "Is laughing ridiculing?",
  "Answer": "Laughing at things that we have taken seriously is being playful, and not a sign of disrespect or contempt for anyone including ourselves. Our laughter takes place with compassion and love for the child."
 },
 {
  "Question": "Why do we need to laugh?",
  "Answer": "The goal is to come to believe that, unlike in the past, in this game, we can see our problems and issues in a positive light and with a sense of humour and joy."
 },
 {
  "Question": "Why do we need continuous laughter?",
  "Answer": "Continuous laughter can be the best antidote to stress"
 },
 {
  "Question": "Why do we need laughing exercises?",
  "Answer": "Laughing exercises are like an antidote for depression, because it turns the topic of depression into a cause for whole-hearted laughter."
 },
 {
  "Question": "How can we apply laughing exercises?",
  "Answer": "After repeated practice of the laughing exercises, we can begin to apply it to things that worry us in the present and the future."
 },
 {
  "Question": "Why do I need to reprocess painful childhood events?",
  "Answer": "In self-attachment one initially gains the skills to enhance positive emotions before tackling childhood traumas through revisiting and reprocessing them."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What makes us laugh?",
  "Answer": "**What makes us laugh?**\\n\\n1- Superiority (Plato): We laugh when we see ourselves as superior to someone\\n\\n2- Incongruity theory (Kant): We laugh at hearing a joke when its punchline violates the expectation built earlier in the joke.\\n\\n3- “Life is a tragedy when seen in close-up, but a comedy in long-shot.” (Charlie Chaplin)\\n\\n4- Evolutionary theory: Laughter developed in higher primates as a play signal."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What are mental exercises?",
  "Answer": "Reading, playing mental games, learning new things, and meditation can all be considered mental exercises."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What is the importance behind the house building exercise?",
  "Answer": "Children’s early attachment in their first two years is created in the pre-verbal development when their visual experience is their most important tool for interaction.\\n\\nHouse building was one of the first activities of early humans and the instinct for it can be inferred when children start to play by creating little rooms and places.\\n\\nThe objective of SAT is to empower the individual through their own actions and creativity in building a grand and robust mansion.\\n\\nEvery stage in building the new house reflects the progress made in repairing the inner world and developing a new orientation in life."
 },
 {
  "Question": "Why can we view SAT and role-playing as a game?",
  "Answer": "SAT is a type of double role-playing game in which the individual plays the role of the child and the adult simultaneously.\\n\\nDonald Winnicott once said: “The general principle seems to me to be valid that psychotherapy is done in the overlap of the two play areas, that of the patient and that of the therapist. If the therapist cannot play, then he is not suitable for the work. If the patient cannot play, then something needs to be done to enable the patient to become able to play, after which psychotherapy can begin. The reason why playing is essential is that it is in playing that the patient is being creative.”\\n\\nChildren learn what they learn and become creative through playing and laughing.\\n\\nThrough comic role-playing, SAT enables the child to become creative. Our problems with properly managing our emotions are usually rooted in our childhood development.\\n\\nThis means that we have not developed the skills to moderate our excitements, regulate our emotions, or have a sense of humour and laugh at times of stress.\\n\\nIn SAT, the adult learns how a good parent interacts with a child, and through role-playing, they become a parent to their child.\\n\\nThe intervention strategy is based on collaboration between the adult and the child for regulating emotions and learning to laugh.\\n\\nThe adult helps the child replace the old derelict house with a brand new one with the aim of realizing the child’s potential and higher goals."
 },
 {
  "Question": "Does SAT really work?",
  "Answer": "The foundation for developing secure attachment is a parent’s unconditional and consistent love.\\n\\nAs seen in the workshops three different experiments have had similar results.\\n\\nThe brain activity of the following groups is measured under fMRI: Mothers and young lovers look at the photos of their children and loved ones respectively; similarly, devout protestants pray.\\n\\nThe activated area of the brain in all three groups is the caudate nucleus, which is the reward centre of the neural network.\\n\\nIn all three groups the area of the brain that is de-activated is the frontal cortex, which is related to negative effects and social judgment.\\n\\nIn all these cases love and emotional relations activated the reward centre of the neural system, and led to the secretion of dopamine, resulting in hope, motivation, and energy for interacting with the loved one. SAT will help us reülicate the secure attachment we all need from parents."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What is the goal setting exercise?",
  "Answer": "Think of a reason why you are doing this therapy, and set yourself a goal of what aspect of your life you want it to improve. This goal should be a non-materialistic goal that guides you towards growth and self-development in society. For example, success in an academic, scientific, literary, philosophical, athletic, spiritual, professional, charitable, manufacturing, or commercial field. If you don’t have a clear goal at the start of the program, you can also try to find it as you practice the protocols."
 },
 {
  "Question": "How should I start this therapy?",
  "Answer": "Think of a reason why you are doing this therapy, and set yourself a goal of what aspect of your life you want it to improve. This goal should be a non-materialistic goal that guides you towards growth and self-development in society. For example, success in an academic, scientific, literary, philosophical, athletic, spiritual, professional, charitable, manufacturing, or commercial field. If you don’t have a clear goal at the start of the program, you can also try to find it as you practice the protocols."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What can I maintain motivation?",
  "Answer": "Think of a reason why you are doing this therapy, and set yourself a goal of what aspect of your life you want it to improve. This goal should be a non-materialistic goal that guides you towards growth and self-development in society. For example, success in an academic, scientific, literary, philosophical, athletic, spiritual, professional, charitable, manufacturing, or commercial field. If you don’t have a clear goal at the start of the program, you can also try to find it as you practice the protocols."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What is the point of exercise 1?",
  "Answer": "In exercise 1, exercise 2.1, and exercise 2.2 we try to distinguish between your adult and your child. Looking at “happy” and “unhappy” child photos helps in this effort. Think about your early years and emotional problems with parents and other significant figures in early childhood. The first principle of SAT is to have a warm and compassionate attitude towards our child, no matter whether the underlying emotions they feel are positive or negative. Later this compassion is extended to other people."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What is the point of exercise Getting to know Your Child?",
  "Answer": "In exercise 1, exercise 2.1, and exercise 2.2 we try to distinguish between your adult and your child. Looking at “happy” and “unhappy” child photos helps in this effort. Think about your early years and emotional problems with parents and other significant figures in early childhood. The first principle of SAT is to have a warm and compassionate attitude towards our child, no matter whether the underlying emotions they feel are positive or negative. Later this compassion is extended to other people."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What is the point of exercise 2.1?",
  "Answer": "In exercise 1, exercise 2.1, and exercise 2.2 we try to distinguish between your adult and your child. Looking at “happy” and “unhappy” child photos helps in this effort. Think about your early years and emotional problems with parents and other significant figures in early childhood. The first principle of SAT is to have a warm and compassionate attitude towards our child, no matter whether the underlying emotions they feel are positive or negative. Later this compassion is extended to other people."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What is the point of exercise Connecting compassionately with your happy child?",
  "Answer": "In exercise 1, exercise 2.1, and exercise 2.2 we try to distinguish between your adult and your child. Looking at “happy” and “unhappy” child photos helps in this effort. Think about your early years and emotional problems with parents and other significant figures in early childhood. The first principle of SAT is to have a warm and compassionate attitude towards our child, no matter whether the underlying emotions they feel are positive or negative. Later this compassion is extended to other people."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What is the point of exercise 2.2?",
  "Answer": "In exercise 1, exercise 2.1, and exercise 2.2 we try to distinguish between your adult and your child. Looking at “happy” and “unhappy” child photos helps in this effort. Think about your early years and emotional problems with parents and other significant figures in early childhood. The first principle of SAT is to have a warm and compassionate attitude towards our child, no matter whether the underlying emotions they feel are positive or negative. Later this compassion is extended to other people."
 },
 {
  "Question": "What is the point of exercise Connecting compassionately with your sad child?",
  "Answer": "In exercise 1, exercise 2.1, and exercise 2.2 we try to distinguish between your adult and your child. Looking at “happy” and “unhappy” child photos helps in this effort. Think about your early years and emotional problems with parents and other significant figures in early childhood. The first principle of SAT is to have a warm and compassionate attitude towards our child, no matter whether the underlying emotions they feel are positive or negative. Later this compassion is extended to other people."
 },
 {

  "Question": "What is the purpose of exercise 3, Singing a song of affection?",

  "Answer": "In exercise 3, 4, and 5 our goal is to cultivate a deep, loving bond with your inner child. It's about establishing a connection that mirrors the nurturing love a parent feels for their child. This involves embracing self-love and expressing affection through gestures like eye contact, holding hands, gentle touches, singing, playing, and laughing. In doing so, we're aiming to trigger the release of dopamine in your brain, akin to the feelings experienced in maternal, romantic, or spiritual love. This not only fosters hope and motivation but also prepares you for an active role in caring for your inner child. Part of this process involves speaking out loud to your inner child, enhancing emotional bonding and maturity. This practice, though often overlooked in adulthood, is crucial for emotional and cognitive development. It represents emotional and cognitive maturity, not a departure from it. Remember, caring for a child is a fundamental human capacity, and these exercises are designed to awaken and reinforce this innate ability within you. The goal of exercise 3 is to cultivate a deep, loving bond with your inner child by singing a song of affection. It involves embracing self-love and expressing affection through gestures like eye contact, holding hands, singing, playing, and laughing all while looking at a happy photo of the child. This is done with the aim of triggering the release of dopamine in your brain, akin to the feelings experienced in maternal, romantic, or spiritual love. This not only fosters hope and motivation but also prepares you for an active role in caring for your inner child."

},

{

  "Question": "What is the purpose of exercise 4, Expressing love and care for the child?",

  "Answer": "In exercise 3, 4, and 5 our goal is to cultivate a deep, loving bond with your inner child. It's about establishing a connection that mirrors the nurturing love a parent feels for their child. This involves embracing self-love and expressing affection through gestures like eye contact, holding hands, gentle touches, singing, playing, and laughing. In doing so, we're aiming to trigger the release of dopamine in your brain, akin to the feelings experienced in maternal, romantic, or spiritual love. This not only fosters hope and motivation but also prepares you for an active role in caring for your inner child. Part of this process involves speaking out loud to your inner child, enhancing emotional bonding and maturity. This practice, though often overlooked in adulthood, is crucial for emotional and cognitive development. It represents emotional and cognitive maturity, not a departure from it. Remember, caring for a child is a fundamental human capacity, and these exercises are designed to awaken and reinforce this innate ability within you. The purpose of exercise 4 is to cultivate a deep, loving bond with your inner child by vocally expressing your love and care toward your childhood self. By repeating the phrase 'I passionately love you and deeply care for you' while genuinely smiling at a happy photo of the child, you foster an emotional connection, enhancing emotional bonding and maturity."

},
{
  "Question": "What is the purpose of exercise 5, Vowing to care for the child?",

  "Answer": "In exercise 3, 4, and 5 our goal is to cultivate a deep, loving bond with your inner child. It's about establishing a connection that mirrors the nurturing love a parent feels for their child. This involves embracing self-love and expressing affection through gestures like eye contact, holding hands, gentle touches, singing, playing, and laughing. In doing so, we're aiming to trigger the release of dopamine in your brain, akin to the feelings experienced in maternal, romantic, or spiritual love. This not only fosters hope and motivation but also prepares you for an active role in caring for your inner child. Part of this process involves speaking out loud to your inner child, enhancing emotional bonding and maturity. This practice, though often overlooked in adulthood, is crucial for emotional and cognitive development. It represents emotional and cognitive maturity, not a departure from it. Remember, caring for a child is a fundamental human capacity, and these exercises are designed to awaken and reinforce this innate ability within you. The purpose of exercise 5 is to uphold a commitment to nurturing your inner child, akin to how a parent cares for their own child. By projecting your own emotions onto the child and vowing out loud to act as a devoted and loving parent, you are reinforcing your emotional bond with the child and taking an active role in their emotional growth and development."

},

{

  "Question": "What is the purpose of exercise 6, Restoring our emotional world after our pledge?",

  "Answer": "In exercise 6, 7, and 8 we focus on the artistic re-creation of our emotional world, an important aspect of our journey towards self-healing and understanding. \n One key element of this process is the concept of house building. Historically, building a house has been a fundamental human activity, providing not only physical protection but also a sense of safety and security. Reflect back to childhood, where building a house or a fort was one of the earliest and most enjoyable games. This activity gave us a feeling of comfort and security, a safe haven of our own making. Now, as we embark on this therapy, think of building a dream house as a metaphor for constructing a new self. It's about creating a space that feels safe, secure, and uniquely ours, where our emotional self can thrive. \n Additionally, we'll explore our bond with nature. Our early connections to nature play a crucial role in our physical and mental health, and they shape our attitudes towards the environment as we grow. Reconnecting with nature now can rekindle those early feelings of attachment, bringing a sense of peace and balance to our lives. Exercise 6 involves rebuilding your emotional world through imagination or drawing. You imagine your emotional world as a home with some derelict parts that you will fully renovate. The new home is intended to provide a safe haven at times of distress for the child and a safe base for the child to tackle life’s challenges. When suffering negative emotions, you imagine that the child is trapped in the basement but can gradually learn to open the door of the basement, walk out and enter the bright rooms, reuniting with the adult."

},

{

  "Question": "What is the purpose of exercise 7.1, maintaining a loving relationship with the child?",

  "Answer": "In exercise 6, 7, and 8 we focus on the artistic re-creation of our emotional world, an important aspect of our journey towards self-healing and understanding. \n One key element of this process is the concept of house building. Historically, building a house has been a fundamental human activity, providing not only physical protection but also a sense of safety and security. Reflect back to childhood, where building a house or a fort was one of the earliest and most enjoyable games. This activity gave us a feeling of comfort and security, a safe haven of our own making. Now, as we embark on this therapy, think of building a dream house as a metaphor for constructing a new self. It's about creating a space that feels safe, secure, and uniquely ours, where our emotional self can thrive. \n Additionally, we'll explore our bond with nature. Our early connections to nature play a crucial role in our physical and mental health, and they shape our attitudes towards the environment as we grow. Reconnecting with nature now can rekindle those early feelings of attachment, bringing a sense of peace and balance to our lives. The purpose of exercise 7.1 is to continue deepening your connection with your inner child by repeatedly expressing your sentiments of love towards them. This exercise leverages the power of verbal affirmations and music to maintain and enhance the warm and loving relationship with your inner child."

},

{

  "Question": "What is the purpose of exercise 7.2, creating a zest for life?",
 
  "Answer": "In exercise 6, 7, and 8 we focus on the artistic re-creation of our emotional world, an important aspect of our journey towards self-healing and understanding. \n One key element of this process is the concept of house building. Historically, building a house has been a fundamental human activity, providing not only physical protection but also a sense of safety and security. Reflect back to childhood, where building a house or a fort was one of the earliest and most enjoyable games. This activity gave us a feeling of comfort and security, a safe haven of our own making. Now, as we embark on this therapy, think of building a dream house as a metaphor for constructing a new self. It's about creating a space that feels safe, secure, and uniquely ours, where our emotional self can thrive. \n Additionally, we'll explore our bond with nature. Our early connections to nature play a crucial role in our physical and mental health, and they shape our attitudes towards the environment as we grow. Reconnecting with nature now can rekindle those early feelings of attachment, bringing a sense of peace and balance to our lives.The purpose of exercise 7.2 is to instill a passion and zest for life within yourself by emphatically singing your favorite song. This activity is aimed to be integrated into your daily routine, and its repetition is supposed to enhance positive emotions and better manage your emotions."

},

{

  "Question": "What is the purpose of exercise 8, Enjoying nature?",

  "Answer": "In exercise 6, 7, and 8 we focus on the artistic re-creation of our emotional world, an important aspect of our journey towards self-healing and understanding. \n One key element of this process is the concept of house building. Historically, building a house has been a fundamental human activity, providing not only physical protection but also a sense of safety and security. Reflect back to childhood, where building a house or a fort was one of the earliest and most enjoyable games. This activity gave us a feeling of comfort and security, a safe haven of our own making. Now, as we embark on this therapy, think of building a dream house as a metaphor for constructing a new self. It's about creating a space that feels safe, secure, and uniquely ours, where our emotional self can thrive. \n Additionally, we'll explore our bond with nature. Our early connections to nature play a crucial role in our physical and mental health, and they shape our attitudes towards the environment as we grow. Reconnecting with nature now can rekindle those early feelings of attachment, bringing a sense of peace and balance to our lives. The purpose of exercise 8 is to establish a strong emotional connection with nature. By spending time in a natural environment and learning to admire and appreciate different elements in nature, it aims to increase joy and reduce negative emotions within you. The goal is to develop an attachment to nature that helps regulate your emotions and makes you want to spend more time in nature after this course ends."

},
{"Question": "Can we do exercise 6, Restoring our emotional world after our pledge?", "Answer":"Through imagination or by drawing, consider your emotional world as a home with some derelict parts that you will fully renovate. The new home is intended to provide a safe haven at times of distress for the child and a safe base for the child to tackle life’s challenges. The new home and its garden is bright and sunny; we imagine carrying out these self-attachment exercises in this environment. The unrestored basement of the new house is the remnant of the derelict house and contains our negative emotions. \n When suffering negative emotions, imagine that the child is trapped in the basement but can gradually learn to open the door of the basement, walk out and enter the bright rooms, reuniting with the adult."},



{"Question": "Can we do exercise 7.1, Maintaining a loving relationship with the child?", "Answer":"Choose some short phrase, e.g., “You are my beautiful child” or “My love”. Say it slowly, out loud at least 5 times as you look at the happy photo/avatar. Then sing your favourite chosen love song at least 5 times. As previously, increase your volume and begin to use your whole body."},



{"Question": "Can we do exercise 7.2, Creating a zest for life?", "Answer":"While looking in a mirror, imagine your image to be that of the child, then begin to loudly sing your previously chosen song. As previously, increase your volume and begin to use your whole body. Do this twice now and then as many times as possible in different circumstances during the day, such as while on the way to work or while cooking dinner, to integrate them into your new life. When singing your favourite song becomes a habit of yours, it becomes an effective tool for enhancing positive affects and managing emotions."},



{"Question": "Can we do exercise 8, Enjoying nature?", "Answer": "Creating an attachment to nature for your child is an effective way to increase joy and reduce negative emotions. On one day this week, go to a local park, wood or forest. Spend at least 5 minutes admiring a tree, attempting to appreciate its real beauty as you have never previously experienced. Repeat this process, including with other aspects of nature (e.g. sky, stars, plants, birds, rivers, sea, your favourite animal), until you feel you have developed an attachment to nature that helps regulate your emotions. Achieving this will help you want to spend more time in nature after this course ends."},

{

  "Question": "What is the purpose of exercise 9, Overcoming Current Negative Emotions?",

  "Answer": "In exercise 9 and 10 we take a significant step: your Adult self will actively work to console and support your Child self, especially in dealing with current or past pains. \n We've been building skills to enhance positive emotions, and now we shift our focus to processing and reducing negative emotions like anger, fear, sadness, and anxiety. These emotions might arise from various aspects of your life, including relationships with partners, family, friends, work, or societal interactions. \n The key here is to project these negative emotions onto your Child self. This allows your Adult self to step in, address, and alleviate these pains, offering the same support and care a nurturing parent would. By engaging in this process, you're not only acknowledging the emotions but actively working to reduce their intensity. \n An essential part of this week's exercises involves self-reassurance and self-massage, which are powerful tools for emotional regulation. These practices aid in releasing oxytocin and vasopressin, hormones that play a crucial role in mitigating feelings of distress and discomfort. \n Moreover, we'll begin reprocessing painful childhood events. Childhood traumas often lead to persistent emotional and behavioral challenges. By starting with less severe cases, you can gradually work your way up to more challenging traumas. It's crucial to only move to more severe traumas when you feel confident and ready. If you're unsure, it's perfectly okay to continue with the exercises from previous weeks and focus on less traumatic experiences until you feel stronger. Exercise 9 involves projecting current negative emotions onto your inner child to help address and alleviate them. By imagining the unhappy photo of your child self and reassuring it aloud, you can start processing these negative emotions. Adding a self-massage to this exercise helps to physically manifest the comforting intent of the exercise, and works to further soothe the emotions."

},

{

  "Question": "What is the purpose of exercise 10, Overcoming Past Pain?",

  "Answer": "In exercise 9 and 10 we take a significant step: your Adult self will actively work to console and support your Child self, especially in dealing with current or past pains. \n We've been building skills to enhance positive emotions, and now we shift our focus to processing and reducing negative emotions like anger, fear, sadness, and anxiety. These emotions might arise from various aspects of your life, including relationships with partners, family, friends, work, or societal interactions. \n The key here is to project these negative emotions onto your Child self. This allows your Adult self to step in, address, and alleviate these pains, offering the same support and care a nurturing parent would. By engaging in this process, you're not only acknowledging the emotions but actively working to reduce their intensity. \n An essential part of this week's exercises involves self-reassurance and self-massage, which are powerful tools for emotional regulation. These practices aid in releasing oxytocin and vasopressin, hormones that play a crucial role in mitigating feelings of distress and discomfort. \n Moreover, we'll begin reprocessing painful childhood events. Childhood traumas often lead to persistent emotional and behavioral challenges. By starting with less severe cases, you can gradually work your way up to more challenging traumas. It's crucial to only move to more severe traumas when you feel confident and ready. If you're unsure, it's perfectly okay to continue with the exercises from previous weeks and focus on less traumatic experiences until you feel stronger. Exercise 10 is about recalling and processing painful childhood memories. You imagine a past scenario where you felt distress or pain, and insert your adult self into the memory to comfort and protect your child self. This includes standing up to any perpetrators and reassuring your child self that they're safe and loved. You repeat these steps until you start feeling comforted and soothed, gradually gaining control over the trauma."

},

{

  "Question": "Can we do exercise 9, Overcoming Current Negative Emotions?",

  "Answer": "With closed eyes, imagine the unhappy photo and project your negative emotions to the unhappy photo representing the Child. While doing this:(i) loudly reassure the Child, and (ii) give your face/neck/head a self-massage. Repeat these steps until you are calmed and comforted."

},

{

  "Question": "Can we do exercise 10, Overcoming Past Pain?",

  "Answer": "With closed eyes, recall a painful childhood episode, such as emotional or physical abuse or loss of a significant figure, with all the details your still remember. Associate the face of the Child you were in the past with the selected unhappy photo. As you remember the associated emotions (e.g., helplessness, humiliation and rage), with closed eyes, imagine your Adult intervening in the scene like a good parent. Imagine your Adult: (i) approaching your Child quickly like any good parent with their child in distress, (ii) loudly reassuring the Child that you have now come to save them, by standing up with a loud voice to any perpetrator, for example: “Why are you hitting my Child?”, and, by supporting the Child with a loud voice, for example: “My darling, I will not let them hurt you anymore”, (iii) imaginatively cuddling your Child, by a face/neck/head self-massage. Repeat (i), (ii), (iii) until comforted and soothed, acquiring mastery over the trauma."

},

{

  "Question": "What is the purpose of exercise 11, Muscle relaxation and playful face for intentional laughing (ET)?",

  "Answer": "In exercise 11, 12, 13 and 14, we focus on the importance of laughter in emotional healing. Laughter, influenced by family and cultural norms, is a natural response that securely attached children often exhibit. While negative reactions to upsets are common, learning to see situations in a different light and finding humor in them is beneficial. We'll encourage your inner child to laugh, fostering a playful attitude and a positive perspective on challenges. Theories of laughter include the Superiority Theory, Incongruity Theory, Relief Theory, Perspective Theory, and Evolutionary Theory. Laughter is a powerful tool for emotion self-regulation, combating anxiety and depression by triggering dopamine and serotonin. It's crucial to maintain a non-hostile attitude in laughter. This week, we'll focus on re-learning to laugh, loosening negative patterns that limit emotional development and the ability to laugh freely, aiding your journey towards emotional freedom. Exercise 11 focuses on reducing the rigidity in our facial and body muscles, which negative patterns can cause. This rigidity can limit the emotional development of our child and our ability to laugh. In this exercise, early in the morning, your Adult self should ask your Child Self to act funny like a child: loosen up facial and body muscles, open up your mouth and sing your favourite song while laughing (or at least smiling) on your own."

},

{

  "Question": "What is the purpose of exercise 12, Victory laughter on our own (ST and IT)?",

  "Answer": "In exercise 11, 12, 13 and 14, we focus on the importance of laughter in emotional healing. Laughter, influenced by family and cultural norms, is a natural response that securely attached children often exhibit. While negative reactions to upsets are common, learning to see situations in a different light and finding humor in them is beneficial. We'll encourage your inner child to laugh, fostering a playful attitude and a positive perspective on challenges. Theories of laughter include the Superiority Theory, Incongruity Theory, Relief Theory, Perspective Theory, and Evolutionary Theory. Laughter is a powerful tool for emotion self-regulation, combating anxiety and depression by triggering dopamine and serotonin. It's crucial to maintain a non-hostile attitude in laughter. This week, we'll focus on re-learning to laugh, loosening negative patterns that limit emotional development and the ability to laugh freely, aiding your journey towards emotional freedom. Exercise 12 is about celebrating small victories with laughter. Immediately after accomplishing something, invite your inner child to smile at the thought of the achievement. Once comfortable with the idea, begin to laugh for at least 10 seconds."

},

{

  "Question": "What is the purpose of exercise 13, Laughing with our childhood self (ST, IT, and ET)?",

  "Answer": "In exercise 11, 12, 13, and 14, we focus on the importance of laughter in emotional healing. Laughter, influenced by family and cultural norms, is a natural response that securely attached children often exhibit. While negative reactions to upsets are common, learning to see situations in a different light and finding humor in them is beneficial. We'll encourage your inner child to laugh, fostering a playful attitude and a positive perspective on challenges. Theories of laughter include the Superiority Theory, Incongruity Theory, Relief Theory, Perspective Theory, and Evolutionary Theory. Laughter is a powerful tool for emotion self-regulation, combating anxiety and depression by triggering dopamine and serotonin. It's crucial to maintain a non-hostile attitude in laughter. This week, we'll focus on re-learning to laugh, loosening negative patterns that limit emotional development and the ability to laugh freely, aiding your journey towards emotional freedom. Exercise 13 focuses on cultivating a joyful connection with your inner child. While looking at a happy photo of your child self, you invite this child aspect to smile and then laugh. This exercise intends to nurture a positive, joyful bond with your inner child."

},

{

  "Question": "What is the purpose of exercise 14, Intentional laughter (ET, IT, and ST)?",

  "Answer": "In exercise 11, 12, 13, and 14, we focus on the importance of laughter in emotional healing. Laughter, influenced by family and cultural norms, is a natural response that securely attached children often exhibit. While negative reactions to upsets are common, learning to see situations in a different light and finding humor in them is beneficial. We'll encourage your inner child to laugh, fostering a playful attitude and a positive perspective on challenges. Theories of laughter include the Superiority Theory, Incongruity Theory, Relief Theory, Perspective Theory, and Evolutionary Theory. Laughter is a powerful tool for emotion self-regulation, combating anxiety and depression by triggering dopamine and serotonin. It's crucial to maintain a non-hostile attitude in laughter. This week, we'll focus on re-learning to laugh, loosening negative patterns that limit emotional development and the ability to laugh freely, aiding your journey towards emotional freedom. Exercise 14 is about developing a habit of intentional laughter. Alone and relaxed, you invite your inner child to repeat a simple, effortless sound in a way that invites laughter. If needed, you can even find humor in the silliness of the exercise itself. The goal is to make this intentional laughter a habit and create a unique style of laughter that fits your personality and style."

},

{

  "Question": "Can we do exercise 11, Muscle relaxation and playful face for intentional laughing (ET)?",

  "Answer": "Just as negative patterns can cause rigidity in our mind and behaviour, they can also lead to rigidity in facial and body muscles, which can limit the emotional development of our child and the ability to laugh. That's why, early in the morning, your Adult self should ask your Child Self to act funny like a child: loosen up facial and body muscles, open up your mouth and sing your favourite song while laughing (or at least smiling) on your own. You can also draw inspiration for your child's solo belly laughter from looking up the terms 'Contagious laughter' and 'Laughter Yoga Brain Break' online."

},

{

  "Question": "Can we do exercise 12, Victory laughter on our own (ST and IT)?",

  "Answer": "Immediately after accomplishing something, e.g. doing household chores, having a conversation with a neighbour, reading an article, or successfully solving a SAT protocol, invite your child to smile at the thought of this as an achievement, then once you are comfortable, begin to laugh for at least 10 seconds."

},

{

  "Question": "Can we do exercise 13, Laughing with our childhood self (ST, IT and ET)?",

  "Answer": "Looking at your happy photo, invite your child to smile and then begin to laugh for at least 10 seconds. Repeat this process at least three times."

},

{

  "Question": "Can we do exercise 14, Intentional laughter (ET, IT	and ST)?",

  "Answer": "At a time when you are alone, open your mouth slightly, loosen your face muscles, raise your eyebrows, then invite your child to slowly and continuously repeat one of the following tones, each of which uses a minimum amount of energy: eh, eh, eh, eh; or ah, ah, ah, ah; or oh, oh, oh, oh; or uh, uh, uh, uh; or ye, ye, ye, ye. If you need a subject to laugh at, you can laugh at the silliness of the exercise! Once this continuous intentional laughter becomes a habit, your child would be able to shape it according to your personality and style to create your own brand of laughter."

},

{



  "Question": "What is the focus of incongruity exercises?",



  "Answer": "In incongruity exercises, the focus is on developing the skill to laugh off our upsets and setbacks, transforming our perspective on negative emotions. A concept of the Gestalt vase is introduced as a tool for changing perspectives. The goal is to learn to shift attention away from negative emotions to a more positive outlook. This objective explores three contexts for compassionate humor: World Incongruities, Self/World Incongruities, and Incongruous Self. The exercises for this session are designed to encourage viewing past challenges as opportunities for laughter and growth."



}, 



{



  "Question": "What is the Gestalt Vase?",



  "Answer": "The Gestalt Vase is a concept used in exercise 15.1 as a tool for changing perspectives. It is a vase that, when viewed differently, reveals two faces. This symbolizes shifting our attention away from negative emotions (the black vase) to a more positive perspective (the white faces). It's about seeing beyond the immediate emotional response to a broader, more optimistic view."



}, 



{



  "Question": "What is exercise 15.1 titled 'Learning to change your perspective' about?",



  "Answer": "Exercise 15.1 involves staring at the black vase and laughing for one minute the moment your perception changes and you see two white faces, conceived as Adult and Child, looking at each other. Then you will stare at the two white faces and laugh for one minute the moment your perception changes and you see the black vase. It is an exercise to help switch perspectives from a negative outlook to a positive one."



},



{



  "Question": "What is the purpose of exercise 15.2 titled 'Incongruous world.'?",



  "Answer": "Exercise 15.2, 'Incongruous world.', involves detecting incongruities and humour in the current system between what it promises via the managers and leaders and what it actually does in accentuating rather than solving our problems, particularly our existential crisis. It is geared towards finding humor and other positive aspects within these mismatches."



},



{



  "Question": "What is Exercise 15.3 'Self-world incongruity' about?",



  "Answer": "Exercise 15.3, titled 'Self-world incongruity.', involves revisiting or managing a recent or current upsetting event against your expectation of life or others. It is about considering these events as opportunities to laugh. It is an exercise in changing perspective and trying to find humor or positivity in unexpected or unsatisfactory outcomes."



},



{



  "Question": "What does Exercise 15.4 'Incongruous self.' involve?",



  "Answer": "Exercise 15.4, 'Incongruous self.', is about practicing being cognizant of any incongruity or discrepancy in your emotional or mental world in the past or present and using them as a reason to laugh without self-depreciation. It's about finding humor in inconsistencies and contradictions in one's life and thoughts."



},



{



  "Question": "What is the aim of Exercise 16 'Learning to be playful about your past pains'?",



  "Answer": "Exercise 16, 'Learning to be playful about your past pains', involves visualizing a painful event that took place in the past that you have struggled with, and despite its painfulness, trying to see a positive impact it has had for you. The aim is to use any of the theories for humor and invite your child to be playful about it and try to laugh at the event. This exercise is about transforming perspective on past painful events and finding humor in them."



},

{



  "Question": "Can we do exercise 15.1, Learning to change your perspective?",



  "Answer": "Stare at the black vase and laugh for one minute the moment your perception changes and you see two white faces, conceived as Adult and Child, looking at each other (IT, ST, PT). Stare at the two white faces and laugh for one minute the moment your perception change and you see the black vase (IT, ST)."



},



{



  "Question": "Can we do exercise 15.2, Incongruous world?",



  "Answer": "Detect incongruities and thus humour in the current system between what it promises via the managers and leaders and what it actually does in accentuating rather than solving our problems in particular our existential crisis."



},



{



  "Question": "Can we do exercise 15.3, Self-world incongruity?",



  "Answer": "Revisit or manage, respectively, a recent or current upsetting event against your expectation of life or others, considering it as an opportunity to laugh by IT."



},



{



  "Question": "Can we do exercise 15.4, Incongruous self?",



  "Answer": "Practice being cognizant of any incongruity or discrepancy in your emotional or mental world in the past or present and use them, by IT, as a reason to laugh without self-depreciation."



},



{



  "Question": "Can we do exercise 16, Learning to be playful about your past pains?",



  "Answer": "Visualize a painful event that took place in the past that you have struggled with, and despite its painfulness, try to see a positive impact it has had for you. Use any of the theories for humour and invite your child to be playful about it and try to laugh at the event."



},

{



  "Question": "What is the Gestalt vase concept?",



  "Answer": "The Gestalt vase is a concept introduced as a tool for changing perspectives. It symbolizes a vase that, when viewed differently, reveals two faces. This represents the idea of shifting our attention away from negative emotions (the black vase) to a more positive perspective (the white faces), allowing us to see beyond the immediate emotional response to a broader, more optimistic view."



},



{



  "Question": "What are the three contexts for compassionate humor?",



  "Answer": "The three contexts for compassionate humor are: 1. World Incongruities - Recognizing the discrepancies between what is said and what is done in the world, particularly in socio-economic and political systems. 2. Self/World Incongruities - Dealing with violations of our expectations from life or others and finding humor in the mismatch between our expectations and reality. 3. Incongruous Self - Finding humor in our own life’s inconsistencies and contradictions, promoting emotional flexibility and wisdom."



}, 
{



  "Question": "Why is laughter considered a form of emotional strength and adaptability?",



  "Answer": "Laughter is considered a form of emotional strength and adaptability because it equips us with the ability to transform our perspective from negative to positive. By learning to laugh at our upsets and setbacks, we cultivate adaptability in dealing with life's challenges, showcasing our emotional strength. This capacity to laugh at difficulties helps us view past challenges as opportunities for growth, rendering us more resilient and joyful."



},


{



  "Question": "What does the quote 'Life is a tragedy when seen in close-up, but a comedy in long-shot.' imply?",



  "Answer": "The quote 'Life is a tragedy when seen in close-up, but a comedy in long-shot.' implies that life's challenges and problems, when seen too closely or taken too seriously, may appear as tragedies. However, if seen from a broader perspective or 'long-shot', they can be transformed into sources of humor and laughter. This quote encourages the reframing of difficulties as opportunities for growth and sources of comedy rather than tragedy."



},

{



  "Question": "What is the focus of Socializing your child exercises?",



  "Answer": "The focus is guiding your Child away from anti-social behaviors and towards identifying a compassionate figure as an ideal role model. It's about recognizing possible narcissistic tendencies fueled by certain social, economic, and cultural factors prevalent in Western societies, and working to transform those tendencies into balanced, compassionate, and empathetic traits. The lesson provides exercises to help identify and nurture these opposite traits, guiding you towards emotional balance and creative thinking."



},



{



  "Question": "What does narcissism have to do with these exercises?",



  "Answer": "Narcissism is a concern because of the observed rise in narcissistic traits in Western societies over recent decades. Such traits, fueled by a competitive economy, the media's focus on individual success and the potential impact of internet and social media, have been normalized but can be detrimental to mental health. An important part of exercises 17, 18, and 19 is to become aware of and manage these narcissistic tendencies in ourselves, understanding how they can be counterproductive to our goals."

},



{



  "Question": "Can we do exercise 17, Identifying patterns of acting out personal resentments?",



  "Answer": "Try to identify any pattern of narcissistic and anti-social feelings that your Child has acted out in your current or past relationships or any long-term resentment borne against someone. Try to recognize how much of your time and energy is consumed in such acting out and bearing resentment. Try to think and feel in opposite ways to these negative feelings."

},



{



  "Question": "Can we do exercise 18, Planning more constructive actions?",



  "Answer": "Work out a new way to handle, in future, what you have identified as acting out anti-social feelings or bearing personal resentment in your life. 1. Without denying these feelings, try to reflect and contain them and avoid acting them out. Try to nurture opposite thoughts and feelings. Try to let go of the personal resentment. This may be hard and challenging but it is necessary for emotional growth. Here, you are taking a critical but constructive stance towards your Child and are exercising foresighted compassion. 2. Find a positive way of re-channeling the aggressive energy invoked by these feelings to productive work (e.g., going for some exercise, talking to a friend, etc.) and ultimately to creative work towards your noble goal in life."

},



{



  "Question": "Can we do exercise 19, Finding and bonding with your compassionate role model?",



  "Answer": "Look in your past life for a compassionate figure who impressed you by being kind and helpful with some words of wisdom when you had problems. For example, an older relative or friend, family acquaintance, teacher, counsellor or therapist who may have passed away or may not be contactable. Remember the emotions you went through when you received kindness and compassion form this figure and how emotional this was for you. Focus your attention and adopt this figure as your idealised role model. Create a platonic loving bond with this figure by singing aloud your favourite love song when remembering all your cherished memories of them. One particular song you may try is 'I cannot help falling in love with you'."

},

{



  "Question": "What is the purpose of exercise 17, Identifying patterns of acting out personal resentments?",



  "Answer": "The purpose of exercises 17, 18, and 19 is to guide your Child away from anti-social behaviors and towards identifying a compassionate figure as an ideal role model. It's important to recognize narcisstic tendencies fueled by various economic, social, and cultural factors, and work to transform those tendencies into balanced, compassionate, and empathetic traits. Specifically, in Exercise 17, you try to identify any pattern of narcissistic and anti-social feelings that your Child has acted out in your current or past relationships or any long-term resentment borne against someone."



},



{



  "Question": "What is the purpose of exercise 18, Planning more constructive actions?",



  "Answer": "The purpose of exercises 17, 18, and 19 is to guide your Child away from anti-social behaviors and towards identifying a compassionate figure as an ideal role model. It's about recognizing narcisstic tendencies fueled by social, economic, and cultural factors, and transforming those tendencies into balanced, compassionate, and empathetic traits. Specifically, for Exercise 18, you work out a new way to handle, in the future, what you have identified as acting out anti-social feelings or bearing personal resentment in your life. You strive to reflect and contain these feelings, avoid acting them out, nurture opposite thoughts and feelings, and let go of the personal resentment."



},



{



  "Question": "What is the purpose of exercise 19, Finding and bonding with your compassionate role model?",



  "Answer": "The purpose of exercises 17, 18, and 19 is to guide your Child away from anti-social behaviors and towards identifying a compassionate figure as an ideal role model. It's about recognizing narcisstic tendencies fueled by social, economic, and cultural factors, and working to transform those tendencies into balanced, compassionate, and empathetic traits. For Exercise 19 specifically, you look in your past life for a compassionate figure who impressed you by being kind and helpful with some words of wisdom when you had problems. You remember the emotions you went through when you received kindness and compassion form this figure and adopt this figure as your idealised role model."

},

{
  "Question": "What is the main focus of the final session in Self Attachment Therapy?",
  "Answer": "The main focus of the final session in Self Attachment Therapy (SAT) is to explore the relationship between one's inner Child and creativity, which is crucial for discovering the true self. The session aims to reignite the secure attachment between the Child and the Adult to help rekindle the individual's creative spark."
},
{
  "Question": "How does having secure attachments early in life influence a child's creativity?",
  "Answer": "Children who develop secure attachments early in life often have a strong capacity for independent thought and reflection. This fosters their ability to discover their true selves, which is the source of their creativity, independence, and spontaneity."
},
{
  "Question": "What is a 'false self' in the context of Self Attachment Therapy?",
  "Answer": "In the context of Self Attachment Therapy, a 'false self' is developed by children who are heavily influenced by their environment, leading to a persona that is constrained by external pressures and lacks genuine spontaneity."
},
{
  "Question": "At what age do children begin to show significant imaginative skills?",
  "Answer": "Children begin to show remarkable imaginative skills and the ability to make connections between different phenomena around the ages of three or four years old, marking the roots of creativity."
},
{
  "Question": "How can external pressures affect a child's natural spontaneity?",
  "Answer": "External pressures can replace a child's natural spontaneity with rigidity and uniformity, limiting their ability to understand events freely and creatively."
},
{
  "Question": "Why is embracing paradoxical traits important in nurturing creativity?",
  "Answer": "Embracing paradoxical traits is key to nurturing creativity because creative individuals often exhibit these traits, such as being energetic yet calm, smart yet naïve, and disciplined yet playful. Recognizing and integrating these paradoxes can enhance one's creative capacities."
},
{
  "Question": "What role do role models, parables, and inspirational quotes play in emotional growth during Self Attachment Therapy?",
  "Answer": "In Self Attachment Therapy, role models, parables, and inspirational quotes are emphasized for their importance in emotional growth. They provide affirmations and encourage individuals to embrace challenges and setbacks, strengthening their willpower and perseverance on their journey towards achieving their goals."
},
{
  "Question": "How is creativity defined in the context of Self Attachment Therapy?",
  "Answer": "In Self Attachment Therapy, creativity is defined not just as artistic expression but as a broader approach to how one perceives the world, solves problems, and approaches life. It is viewed as an essential aspect of a fulfilled and balanced life, stemming from one's inner Child."
},

{



  "Question": "What is the purpose of Exercise 20, Updating our rigid beliefs to enhance creativity?",



  "Answer": "In exercises 20 and 21 we'll delve into the relationship between your inner Child and your creativity, an essential aspect of discovering your true self. Children who develop secure attachments early in life tend to have a strong capacity for independent thought and reflection. This fosters their ability to discover their true selves, which is the very source of their creativity, independence, and spontaneity. In contrast, a child influenced heavily by their environment might develop what's called a 'false self', constrained by external pressures and lacking genuine spontaneity. At around three or four years old, children begin to show remarkable imaginative skills and the ability to make connections between different phenomena – the roots of creativity. A child’s natural spontaneity helps them to understand events without any rigid preconceptions. However, external pressures can sometimes replace this spontaneity with rigidity and uniformity. Our goal in SAT is to rekindle this secure attachment between the Child and the Adult, reigniting your creative spark. Additionally, creative individuals often exhibit paradoxical traits – they are energetic yet calm, smart yet naïve, disciplined yet playful, and so on. Embracing these paradoxes is key to nurturing your creativity. This week, we also focus on the importance of role models, parables, and inspirational quotes in emotional growth. Affirmations from your chosen compassionate role model can strengthen your willpower and perseverance. They encourage you to embrace challenges and setbacks as part of your journey towards achieving your goals. Remember the words of Nietzsche, 'What does not kill me makes me stronger.' This perspective encourages embracing life's challenges with love and strength, seeing them as opportunities for growth. As we conclude our therapy, it's important to realize that creativity isn't just about artistic expression; it's about how you approach life, solve problems, and perceive the world around you. Your inner Child is a wellspring of creativity, and nurturing this aspect of yourself is crucial for a fulfilled and balanced life. The purpose of Exercise 20, Updating our rigid beliefs to enhance creativity, is to challenge your usual ideological framework to weaken any one-sided belief patterns and encourage spontaneity and examination of any issue from multiple perspectives. It involves practicing this with subjects or themes that you have deep-rooted beliefs about and you are also interested in. This does not mean that you would change your viewpoint but it allows you to see the subject from different perspectives and to be able to put yourself in other people’s shoes."



},


{



  "Question": "What is the purpose of Exercise 21, Practicing affirmations?",



  "Answer": "In exercises 20 and 21 we'll delve into the relationship between your inner Child and your creativity, an essential aspect of discovering your true self. Children who develop secure attachments early in life tend to have a strong capacity for independent thought and reflection. This fosters their ability to discover their true selves, which is the very source of their creativity, independence, and spontaneity. In contrast, a child influenced heavily by their environment might develop what's called a 'false self', constrained by external pressures and lacking genuine spontaneity. At around three or four years old, children begin to show remarkable imaginative skills and the ability to make connections between different phenomena – the roots of creativity. A child’s natural spontaneity helps them to understand events without any rigid preconceptions. However, external pressures can sometimes replace this spontaneity with rigidity and uniformity. Our goal in SAT is to rekindle this secure attachment between the Child and the Adult, reigniting your creative spark. Additionally, creative individuals often exhibit paradoxical traits – they are energetic yet calm, smart yet naïve, disciplined yet playful, and so on. Embracing these paradoxes is key to nurturing your creativity. This week, we also focus on the importance of role models, parables, and inspirational quotes in emotional growth. Affirmations from your chosen compassionate role model can strengthen your willpower and perseverance. They encourage you to embrace challenges and setbacks as part of your journey towards achieving your goals. Remember the words of Nietzsche, 'What does not kill me makes me stronger.' This perspective encourages embracing life's challenges with love and strength, seeing them as opportunities for growth. As we conclude our therapy, it's important to realize that creativity isn't just about artistic expression; it's about how you approach life, solve problems, and perceive the world around you. Your inner Child is a wellspring of creativity, and nurturing this aspect of yourself is crucial for a fulfilled and balanced life. The purpose of Exercise 21, Practicing affirmations, is to put together a list of inspirational affirmations by figures you admire. You select the three that inspire you most, read them out and repeat slowly for at least 3 minutes. It is focused on using inspirational affirmations as a tool to strengthen your willpower and perseverance, encouraging you to embrace challenges and setbacks as part of your journey towards achieving your goals."



},
{
  "Question": "Can we do Exercise 20?",
  "Answer": "Updating our rigid beliefs to enhance creativity: Challenge your usual ideological framework to weaken any one-sided belief patterns and encourage spontaneity and examination of any issue from multiple perspectives. Practice this with subjects or themes that you have deep-rooted beliefs about and you are also interested in. This may include any social, political, or ethical issue, such as marriage, sexual orientation or racism. For example, whatever your political viewpoint on a specific subject is, consider the subject both from a liberal and conservative or from a left-wing and right-wing point of view and try to understand both sides of the issue and challenge your dominant ideological framework. This does not mean that you would change your viewpoint but it allows you to see the subject from different perspectives and to be able to put yourself in other people’s shoes. Consider a different question or issue daily for at least 5 minutes."
},
{
  "Question": "Can we do Exercise 21?",
  "Answer": "Practicing affirmations: Put together a list of inspirational affirmations by figures you admire. Choose the three that inspire you most. Read them out and repeat slowly for at least 3 minutes."
}


]
}